Panos Tsapanidis

Fullstack developer with a focus on frontend. I have a good eye for detail and a passion for user experience. I quickly embrace new technologies and approach challenges with a positive attitude while bringing a strong sense of responsibility and professionalism to every project.

EXPERIENCE

Redmind

November 2022 - ongoing - Developer - Stockholm

As a fullstack developer at Redmind, I work closely with the design team, turning their Figma designs into web and app screens by using ReactJS and React Native. In addition, I built backend infrastructure using NodeJS and Firebase. I am a proactive team member focused on improving the user experience and streamlining the development process.

SVØRN

April 2014 - December 2021 — Self-employed — Stockholm

As a self-employed entrepreneur, I ran a successful men's fashion accessories business with a mix of D2C (Shopify) and B2B sales, supported by newsletters, SEO, and social media. Also created graphics (mockup for website and marketing material) using Photoshop and InDesign.

PROJECT

Redmind/Moveat

December 2022 - ongoing — Fullstack developer — Stockholm

Moveat is a multi-platform app that sells tickets for users to take part in taste tours in Scandinavia. With up to 8 taste stops, users can create their own route and follow their own pace.

Using ReactJS, React Native and TypeScript, I turn Figma designs into dynamic content. My knowledge in JavaScript and TypeScript allows me to implement features like checkout functionality and interact with the database on Frontend. I also use React packages to build features like Google static map and drag & drop functionality. To interact with the project's database (powered by Firebase), I use NodeJS to create routes and requests, connecting the frontend and the backend.

EDUCATION

Web Developer Fullstack Open Source

August 2021 - May 2023 — Nackademin — Stockholm

React.js, JavaScript, TypeScript, Node.js/Express.js, Next.js, EJS, MongoDB, MySQL, Git, Wordpress, Docker, CSS/SASS, CI/CD, Jest

The degree gives me broad skills in both backend and frontend development. We develop interactive web applications with NodeJS, JavaScript and TypeScript as well as HTML, CSS, various libraries and frameworks such as ReactJS, EJS and MongoDB and MySQL. During my studies I have built a Fullstack e-commerce application, using ReactJS, CSS, TypeScript, NodeJS and MongoDB.



Technical Skills

React, React Native, JavaScript, TypeScript, Node.js, MongoDB, Firebase, Next.js, EJS, Wordpress, HTML, CSS/ SASS, Git, Figma, Scrum, Agile, Mob programming, SEO, Photoshop, InDesign, Jest

Languages

Swedish, English, Greek

https://github.com/panosjapan7

https://www.linkedin.com/in/panostsapanidis/